Guide to the Strong Family Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- JOSEPHINE E. STRONG PAPERS, 1812-1925; Series I; 5 linear feet (13 boxes)
  This series contains material arranged in two sections: Josephine E. Strong Papers and Other Family Papers.
  - Josephine E. Strong Papers
    - Correspondence: outgoing, 1852-1894, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
    - Correspondence: incoming
      - Clapp, Henry L., 1870-1906 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        General note
        See also: boxes 2-7, folders 13-70
      - General
        - 1845-1854 (Box 1, Folder 8-11)
        - 1855-1862 (Box 2, Folder 12-22)
        - 1863-1866 August (Box 3, Folder 23-34)
          (No folder 25)
        - 1866 September - 1885 (Box 4, Folder 35-45)
        - 1886-1907, undated (Box 5, Folder 46-56)
        - undated (Box 6, Folder 57-67)
        - undated (Box 7, Folder 68-70)
      - Personal papers
        - Bankbooks, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 71)
        - Compositions, 1853-1857, no date
          See: box 1, folder 6
        - Diaries
          - 1895-1908 (Box 6, Folder 72-75)
          - 1910-1911 (Box 8, Folder 76)
        - Drawing book, 1865 (Box 8, Folder 77)
        - Estate papers, 1911-1913 (Box 8, Folder 78)
        - Financial papers, 1899-1912 (Box 8, Folder 79-80)
        - Massachusetts House of Representatives rule book, 1852, 1855 (Box 8, Folder 81-82)
        - Legal papers, undated (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - Personal papers
      - Notebook, 1899-1910 (Box 9, Folder 84)
      - Massachusetts Senate rule book, 1855 (Box 9, Folder 85)
      - Miscellanea, 1864-1872, n.d (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Other Family Papers
    - General correspondence
      - 1816-1861 (Box 10, Folder 87-96)
        See also: Oversize
      - 1862-1892 (Box 11, Folder 97-107)
      - 1894-1911, undated (Box 12, Folder 108-116)
    - Personal papers
      - Strong, Henry Hastings
        - Diary, 1885, 1912-1913 (Box 12, Folder 117)
        - Miscellanea, 1878-1911 (Box 12, Folder 118)
          See also: box 13, folder 129
      - Strong, Noah Lyman
        - Legal and financial papers, 1834-1879 (Box 13, Folder 119-121)
        - Mortgages, 1865-1868, 1891 (Box 13, Folder 122-123)
        - Miscellanea, 1842-1893 (Box 13, Folder 124-125)
      - Other
        - Compositions, poetry, [1840s-1850s] (Box 13, Folder 126)
        - Legal and financial papers, 1812-1886 (Box 13, Folder 127-128)
        - Photographs, undated (Box 13, Folder 129)
          See also: box 16
        - Frederick Strong Kingsley photographs, 1882-1912
        - Printed material, 1924-1925, undated (Box 13, Folder 130-131)
- STRONG FAMILY PAPERS, 1667-1884; Series II; .75 linear feet (2 boxes)
  This series contains material arranged in three sections: Chatham - Cyprian Strong; Milford; and Norwich.
  - Chatham--Cyprian Strong
    - Account book, 1770-1799 (Box 14, Folder 132)
    - Correspondence, 1793, 1800, undated (Box 14, Folder 133)
    - Manuscripts and sermons, 1761-1793, undated (Box 14, Folder 134)
  - Milford
    - Legal papers, 1667-1786 (Box 14, Folder 135)
    - Pond family
      - Correspondence and papers, 1777-1826 (Box 14, Folder 136)
      - Autograph collection and miscellanea, 1739-1884 (Box 14, Folder 137)
    - Strong, Ephraim
      - Church papers, 1741-1764, undated (Box 14, Folder 138)
      - Correspondence, 1736-1753, undated (Box 14, Folder 139)
      - Justice of the peace papers, 1771-1792, undated (Box 14, Folder 140)
      - Personal legal and financial papers, 1731-1801 (Box 14, Folder 141)
  - Norwich
    - Huntington, Eunice Carew, 1804, 1834, 1838, undated (Box 14, Folder 142)
    - Huntington, Lucy Coit, 1765-1774, undated (Box 14, Folder 143)
    - Huntington, Lydia Coit, 1821 (Box 14, Folder 144)
    - Strong, Henry
      - Account books, 1825-1852 (Box 14, Folder 145)
      - Legal notebooks, undated (Box 15, Folder 146)
    - Strong, Joseph, 1766-1796 (Box 15, Folder 147)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 15, Folder 148)
- OVERSIZE, Series III
  - Photographs (Box 16)
  - General correspondence [Folio] (Box 17)